const questions=[
    {
      question: "Stack is also called as",
      options: [
        "First in first out",
        "First in last out",
        "Last in last out",
        "Last in first out"
      ],
      answer: "Last in first out"
    },
    {
      question: "Any node is the path from the root to the node is called",
      options: [
        "Ancestor node",
        "Successor node",
        "Internal node",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      answer: "Ancestor node"
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the following is not the type of queue?",
      options: [
        "Priority queue",
        "Circular queue",
        "Single ended queue",
        "Ordinary queue"
      ],
      answer: "Single ended queue"
    },
    {
      question: "A graph is a collection of nodes, called ...... And line segments called arcs  or  that connect pair of nodes.",
      options: [
        "vertices, paths",
        "vertices, edges",
        "graph node, edges",
        "edges, vertices"
      ],
      answer: "vertices, edges"
    },
    {
      question: "In ........, search start at the beginning of the list and check every element in  the list.",
      options: [
        "Binary search",
        "Hash Search",
        "Linear search",
        "Binary Tree search"
      ],
      answer: "Linear search"
    },
    {
      question: "In the  traversal we process all of a vertex's descendants before we move to an adjacent vertex.",
      options: [
        "Depth Limited",
        "With First",
        "Breadth First",
        "Depth First"
      ],
      answer: "Depth First"
    },
    {
      question: "To represent hierarchical relationship between elements, Which data structure is suitable?",
      options: [
        "Graph",
        "Tree",
        "Dequeue",
        "Priority"
      ],
      answer: "Tree"
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the following data structure is linear type?",
      options: [
        "Stack",
        "Graph",
        "Trees",
        "Binary tree"
      ],
      answer: "Stack"
    },
    {
      question: "Herder node is used as sentinel in",
      options: [
        "Queues",
        "Stacks",
        "Graphs",
        "Binary tree"
      ],
      answer: "Binary tree"
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the following data structure can't store the nonhomogeneous data elements?",
      options: [
        "Arrays",
        "Stacks",
        "Records",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      answer: "Arrays"
    },
    {
      question: "A binary search tree whose left subtree and right subtree differ in hight by at  most 1 unit is called",
      options: [
        "Lemma tree",
        "Redblack tree",
        "AVL tree",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      answer: "AVL tree"
    },
    {
      question: "...... is a pile in which items are added at one end and removed from the  other.",
      options: [
        "List",
        "Queue",
        "Stack",
        "Array"
      ],
      answer: "Queue"
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the following is non-linear data structure?",
      options: [
        "Trees",
        "Stacks",
        "Strings",
        "All of the above"
      ],
      answer: "Trees"
    },
    {
      question: "The number of comparisons done by sequential search is",
      options: [
        "$(N/2)+1$",
        "$(N+1)/2$",
        "$(N-1)/2$",
        "$(N-2)/2$"
      ],
      answer: "$(N+1)/2$"
    },
    {
      question: "...... is not the operation that can be performed on queue.",
      options: [
        "Traversal",
        "Insertion",
        "Deletion",
        "Retrieval"
      ],
      answer: "Traversal"
    },
    {
      question: "Which is/are the application(s) of stack",
      options: [
        "Function calls",
        "Large number Arithmetic",
        "Evaluation of arithmetic expressions",
        "All of the above"
      ],
      answer: "All of the above"
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the following data structures are indexed structures?",
      options: [
        "Stack",
        "Linked lists",
        "Linear arrays",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      answer: "Linear arrays"
    },
     {
      question: "Which of the following data structure store the homogeneous data elements?",
      options: [
        "Lists",
        "Pointers",
        "Records",
        "Arrays"
      ],
      answer: "Records"
    },
    {
      question: "Linear arrays are also called.......",
      options: [
        "One-dimensional array",
        "Vertical array",
        "Horizontal array",
        "All of the above"
      ],
      answer: "One-dimensional array"
    },
    {
      question: "A  does not keep track of address of every element in the list.",
      options: [
        "Stack",
        "Queue",
        "String",
        "Linear array"
      ],
      answer: "Linear array"
    },
    {
      question: "The complexity of linear search algorithm is",
      options: [
        "$O(n)$",
        "(log n)",
        "$0(n2)$",
        "O(n log n)"
      ],
      answer: "$O(n)$"
    },
    {
      question: "The complexity of Binary search algorithm is",
      options: [
        "$O(n)$",
        "(log n)",
        "$O(n2)$",
        "O(n log n)"
      ],
      answer: "(log n)"
    },
    {
      question: "The complexity of Bubble sort algorithm is",
      options: [
        "$O(n)$",
        "(log n)",
        "$O(n2)$",
        "O(n log n)"
      ],
      answer: "$O(n2)$"
    },
    {
      question: "The complexity of merge sort algorithm is",
      options: [
        "$O(n)$",
        "(log n)",
        "$O(n2)$",
        "O(n log n)"
      ],
      answer: "O(n log n)"
    },
    {
      question: "The space factor when determining the efficiency of algorithm is measured  by",
      options: [
        "Counting the maximum memory needed by the algorithm",
        "Counting the minimum memory needed by the algorithm",
        "Counting the average memory needed by the algorithm",
        "Counting the maximum disk space needed by the algorithm"
      ],
      answer: "Counting the maximum memory needed by the algorithm"
    },
    {
      question: "The operation of processing each element in the list is known as",
      options: [
        "Traversal",
        "Inserting",
        "Merging",
        "Sorting"
      ],
      answer: "Traversal"
    },
    {
      question: "Binary trees with threads are called as.",
      options: [
        "Special trees",
        "Pointer trees",
        "Threaded trees",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      answer: "Threaded trees"
    },
    {
      question: "In Binary trees nodes with no successor are called......",
      options: [
        "End nodes",
        "Final nodes",
        "Last nodes",
        "Terminal nodes"
      ],
      answer: "Terminal nodes"
    },
    {
      question: "The depth of a complete binary tree is given by",
      options: [
        "Dn = n log 2n",
        "Dn = n log 2n+1",
        "Dn = log 2n",
        "Dn = log 2n+1"
      ],
      answer: "Dn = log 2n+1"
    },
    {
      question: "Every node N in a binary tree T except the root has a unique parent called  the ... of N.",
      options: [
        "Predecessor",
        "Antecedents",
        "Precursor",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      answer: "Predecessor"
    },
    {
      question: "The in order traversal of tree will yield a sorted listing of elements of tree  in....",
      options: [
        "Merging",
        "AVL Trees",
        "Binary trees",
        "Binary search trees"
      ],
      answer: "Binary search trees"
    },
    {
      question: "A binary tree whose every node has either zero or two children is  called..",
      options: [
        "Extended binary tree",
        "Complete binary tree",
        "Binary Search tree",
        "Disjoint tree"
      ],
      answer: "Extended binary tree"
    },
    {
      question: "The post order traversal of a binary tree is DEBFCA.  Find out the pre order  traversal",
      options: [
        "ABFCDE",
        "ADBFEC",
        "ABDECF",
        "ABDCEF"
      ],
      answer: "ABDECF"
    },
    {
      question: "Three standards ways of traversing a binary tree T with root R",
      options: [
        "Prefix, infix, postfix",
        "Pre-process, in-process, post-process",
        "Pre-traversal, in-traversal, post-traversal",
        "Pre-order, in-order, post-order"
      ],
      answer: "Pre-order, in-order, post-order"
    },
    {
      question: "A technique for direct search is",
      options: [
        "Hashing",
        "Tree Search",
        "Binary Search",
        "Linear Search"
      ],
      answer: "Hashing"
    },
    {
      question: "If a node having two children is deleted from a binary tree, it is replaced by  its",
      options: [
        "Preorder predecessor",
        "Inorder predecessor",
        "Inorder successor",
        "Preorder successor"
      ],
      answer: "Inorder successor"
    },
     {
      question: "A full binary tree with $2n+1$ nodes contain",
      options: [
        "n leaf nodes",
        "n non-leaf nodes",
        "n-1 leaf nodes",
        "n-1 non-leaf nodes"
      ],
      answer: "n non-leaf nodes"
    },
    {
      question: "A full binary tree with n leaves contains",
      options: [
        "n-1 nodes",
        "log2n nodes",
        "2n-1 nodes",
        "$2^{n}$ nodes"
      ],
      answer: "2n-1 nodes"
    },
    {
      question: "The smallest element of an array's index is called its",
      options: [
        "extraction",
        "range",
        "lower bound",
        "upper bound"
      ],
      answer: "lower bound"
    },
    {
      question: "The data structure required for Breadth First Traversal on a graph is",
      options: [
        "queue",
        "stack",
        "array",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      answer: "queue"
    },
    {
      question: "One can convert a binary tree into its mirror image by traversing it in",
      options: [
        "inorder",
        "preorder",
        "postorder",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      answer: "postorder"
    },
    {
      question: "The data structure required to evaluate a postfix expression is",
      options: [
        "queue",
        "stack",
        "linked-list",
        "All of the above"
      ],
      answer: "stack"
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the following sorting methods would be most suitable for sorting a list which is almost sorted",
      options: [
        "Insertion Sort",
        "Selection Sort",
        "Quick Sort",
        "Bubble Sort"
      ],
      answer: "Bubble Sort"
    },
    {
      question: "The process of accessing data stored in a serial access memory is similar to manipulating data on a",
      options: [
        "heap",
        "queue",
        "stack",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      answer: "stack"
    },
    {
      question: "The postfix form of A*B+C/D is",
      options: [
        "ABCD+/*",
        "AB*CD/+",
        "*AB/CD+",
        "A*BC+/D"
      ],
      answer: "AB*CD/+"
    },
    {
      question: "A linear collection of data elements where the linear node is given by  means of  pointer is called",
      options: [
        "linked list",
        "node list",
        "primitive list",
        "None of these"
      ],
      answer: "linked list"
    },
    {
      question: "Representation of data structure in memory is known as:",
      options: [
        "storage structure",
        "file structure",
        "abstract data type",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      answer: "abstract data type"
    },
    {
      question: "The goal of hashing is to produce a search that takes",
      options: [
        "O(1) time",
        "O(n2) time",
        "O(log n) time",
        "O(n log n) time"
      ],
      answer: "O(1) time"
    },
    {
      question: "The complexity of multiplying two matrices of order m*n and n*p is",
      options: [
        "np",
        "mn+p",
        "mn",
        "mnp"
      ],
      answer: "mnp"
    },
    {
      question: "For an undirected graph with n vertices and e edges, the sum of the degree of  each vertex is equal to",
      options: [
        "2n",
        "2e",
        "(e2+1)/2",
        "(2n-1)/2"
      ],
      answer: "2e"
    },
    {
      question: "Which data structure allows deleting data elements from and inserting at  rear?",
      options: [
        "Stacks",
        "Queues",
        "Dequeues",
        "Binary search tree"
      ],
      answer: "Queues"
    },
    {
      question: "Which data structure is used in breadth first search of a graph to hold nodes?",
      options: [
        "Array",
        "Tree",
        "Stack",
        "queue"
      ],
      answer: "queue"
    },
    {
      question: "Identify the data structure which allows deletions at both ends of the list but insertion at only one end.",
      options: [
        "Stack",
        "Priority queues",
        "Output restricted qequeue",
        "Input restricted dequeue"
      ],
      answer: "Input restricted dequeue"
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the following data structure is non linear type?",
      options: [
        "Graph",
        "Stacks",
        "Lists",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      answer: "Graph"
    },
    {
      question: "In a queue, the initial values of front pointer f rare pointer r should be …….. and ……….. respectively.",
      options: [
        "0 and 1",
        "0 and -1",
        "-1 and 0",
        "1 and 0"
      ],
      answer: "0 and -1"
    },
    {
      question: "There is an extra element at the head of the list called a .........",
      options: [
        "Sentinel",
        "Antinel",
        "List head",
        "List header"
      ],
      answer: "Sentinel"
    },
    {
      question: "The property of binary tree is",
      options: [
        "The root cannot contain NULL",
        "The first subset is called left subtree",
        "The second subtree is called right subtree",
        "The right subtree can be empty"
      ],
      answer: "The right subtree can be empty"
    },
    {
      question: "When new data are to be inserted into a data structure, but there is not  available space;  this situation is usually called .......",
      options: [
        "overflow",
        "Underflow",
        "housefull",
        "memoryfull"
      ],
      answer: "overflow"
    },
    {
      question: "A data structure where elements can be added or removed at either end but"
    },
  [
    {
      question: "not in the middle is called ......",
      options: [
        "stacks",
        "queues",
        "dequeue",
        "linked lists"
      ],
      answer: "dequeue"
    },
    {
      question: "The use of pointers to refer elements of a data structure in which elements  are logically adjacent is ......",
      options: [
        "stack",
        "queue",
        "pointers",
        "linked allocation"
      ],
      answer: "linked allocation"
    },
    {
      question: "Binary search algorithm cannot be applied to...",
      options: [
        "pointer array",
        "sorted linear array",
        "sorted binary trees",
        "sorted linked list"
      ],
      answer: "pointer array"
    },
    {
      question: "............ is the method used by card sorter?",
      options: [
        "Quick",
        "Heap",
        "Insertion",
        "Radix sort"
      ],
      answer: "Radix sort"
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the following conditions checks available free space in avail list?",
      options: [
        "Avail=Top",
        "Null=Avail",
        "Avail=Null",
        "Avail=Max stack"
      ],
      answer: "Avail=Null"
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the following is not the type of queue?",
      options: [
        "Priority queue",
        "Circular queue",
        "Ordinary queue",
        "Single ended queue"
      ],
      answer: "Single ended queue"
    },
    {
      question: "........ is a directed tree in which outdegree of each node is less than or  equal to two.",
      options: [
        "Binary tree",
        "Dinary tree",
        "Unary tree",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      answer: "Binary tree"
    },
    {
      question: "The number of comparisons done by sequential search is .......",
      options: [
        "(N/2)-1",
        "(N+1)/2",
        "(N-1)/2",
        "(N+2)/2"
      ],
      answer: "(N+1)/2"
    },
    {
      question: "In ......, search start at the beginning of the list and check every element in  the list.",
      options: [
        "Hash Search",
        "Binary search",
        "Linear search",
        "Binary Tree search"
      ],
      answer: "Linear search"
    },
    {
      question: "The operation that combines the element is of A and B in a single sorted list  C with n=r+s element is called.......",
      options: [
        "Sharing",
        "Merging",
        "Inserting",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      answer: "Merging"
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the following is an internal sorting?",
      options: [
        "2-way Merge Sort",
        "Tape Sort",
        "Merge Sort",
        "Tree Sort"
      ],
      answer: "Tree Sort"
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the following is an external sorting?",
      options: [
        "Merge Sort",
        "Tree Sort",
        "Bubble Sort",
        "Insertion Sort"
      ],
      answer: "Merge Sort"
    },
    {
      question: "...... is the term used to insert an element into stack?",
      options: [
        "Push",
        "Pull",
        "Pop",
        "All of the above"
      ],
      answer: "Push"
    },
    {
      question: ".......... is the term used to delete an element from the stack?",
      options: [
        "Push",
        "Pull",
        "Pop",
        "All of the above"
      ],
      answer: "Pop"
    },
    {
      question: "Before inserting into stack one must check the condition.........",
      options: [
        "Overflow",
        "Underflow",
        "Maximum elements",
        "Existing elements"
      ],
      answer: "Overflow"
    },
    {
      question: "Deletion in the linked stack takes place by deleting........",
      options: [
        "Beginning of the list",
        "End of the list",
        "Middle of the list",
        "Node pointed by the start process."
      ],
      answer: "Node pointed by the start process."
    },
    {
      question: "The value of REAR is increased by 1 when.......",
      options: [
        "An element is merged in a queue",
        "An element is added in a queue",
        "An element is traversed in a queue",
        "An element is deleted in a queue"
      ],
      answer: "An element is added in a queue"
    },
    {
      question: "The operation of processing each element in the list is known as......",
      options: [
        "merging",
        "traversal",
        "inserting",
        "sorting"
      ],
      answer: "traversal"
    },
    {
      question: "Sequential representation of binary tree uses........",
      options: [
        "Array with pointers",
        "Single linear array",
        "Two dimensional arrays",
        "Three dimensional arrays"
      ],
      answer: "Array with pointers"
    },
    {
      question: "In a 2-tree, nodes with 0 children are called............",
      options: [
        "Outer node",
        "Exterior node",
        "External node",
        "Outside node"
      ],
      answer: "External node"
    },
    {
      question: "In a extended-binary tree nodes with 2 children are called........",
      options: [
        "Inner node",
        "Internal node",
        "Domestic node",
        "Interior node"
      ],
      answer: "Internal node"
    },
    {
      question: "The line drawn from a node N of tree T to a successor is called .......",
      options: [
        "Route",
        "Arrow",
        "Edge",
        "Path"
      ],
      answer: "Edge"
    },
    {
      question: "Which of the following sorting algorithms does not have a worst case  running time of O(n2)?",
      options: [
        "Insertion sort",
        "Quick sort",
        "Bubble sort",
        "Merge sort"
      ],
      answer: "Merge sort"
    },
    {
      question: "In a circular linked list",
      options: [
        "there is no beginning and no end.",
        "components are arranged hierarchically.",
        "forward and backward traversal within the list is permitted.",
        "components are all linked together in some sequential manner."
      ],
      answer: "there is no beginning and no end."
    },
    {
      question: "The quick sort algorithm exploit _________ design technique",
      options: [
        "Overflow",
        "Backtracking",
        "Dynamic programming",
        "Divide and Conquer"
      ],
      answer: "Divide and Conquer"
    },
    {
      question: "The data structure required to check whether an expression contains  balanced parenthesis is",
      options: [
        "Stack",
        "Queue",
        "Tree",
        "Array"
      ],
      answer: "Stack"
    },
    {
      question: "What data structure would you mostly likely see in a nonrecursive  implementation of a recursive algorithm?",
      options: [
        "Trees",
        "Linked list",
        "Stack",
        "Queue"
      ],
      answer: "Stack"
    },
    {
      question: "The number of leaf nodes in a complete binary tree of depth d is",
      options: [
        "2d",
        "2d–1+1",
        "2d+1+1",
        "2d+1"
      ],
      answer: "2d"
    },
    {
      question: "The pre-order and post order traversal of a Binary Tree generates the same  output.  The tree can have maximum",
      options: [
        "One node",
        "Two nodes",
        "Three nodes",
        "Any number of nodes"
      ],
      answer: "One node"
    },
    {
      question: "A binary tree of depth “d” is an almost complete binary tree if",
      options: [
        "Each leaf in the tree is either at level “d” or at level “d–1”",
        "For any node “n” in the tree with a right descendent at level “d” all the left descendents of “n” that are leaves, are also at level “d”",
        "Both (A) & (B)",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      answer: "Both (A) & (B)"
    },
    {
      question: "In a binary tree a sequence of consecutive edges is called ...... A",
      options: [
        "Path",
        "Rotate",
        "Two-way",
        "Connecting lines"
      ],
      answer: "Path"
    },
    {
      question: "An adjacency matrix representation of a graph cannot contain information of:",
      options: [
        "nodes",
        "edges",
        "parallel edges",
        "direction of edges"
      ],
      answer: "parallel edges"
    },
    {
      question: "........ is not the operation that can be performed on queue.",
      options: [
        "Traversal",
        "Retrieval",
        "Deletion",
        "Insertion"
      ],
      answer: "Traversal"
    },
    {
      question: "A linear list in which the last node points to the first node is ........",
      options: [
        "singly linked list",
        "doubly linked list",
        "circular linked list",
        "none of the above"
      ],
      answer: "circular linked list"
    },
    {
      question: "A linear list in which the pointer points only to the successive node is......",
      options: [
        "singly linked list",
        "circular linked list",
        "doubly linked list",
        "none of the above"
      ],
      answer: "singly linked list"
    },
    {
      question: "A ...... indicates the end of the list.",
      options: [
        "Guard",
        "Sentinel",
        "End pointer",
        "Last pointer"
      ],
      answer: "Sentinel"
    },
    {
      question: "LLINK is the pointer pointing to the ......",
      options: [
        "head node",
        "last node",
        "successor node",
        "predecessor node"
      ],
      answer: "predecessor node"
    },
    {
      question: "Indexing the........ element in the list is not possible in linked lists.",
      options: [
        "first",
        "middle",
        "last",
        "All of the above"
      ],
      answer: "middle"
    },
    {
      question: "A doubly linked list has .......... pointers with each node.",
      options: [
        "0",
        "1",
        "2",
        "3"
      ],
      answer: "2"
    },
    {
      question: "A linear list in which each node has point to the predecessor and  successors nodes is called ........",
      options: [
        "singly linked list",
        "linear linked list",
        "doubly linked list",
        "None of the above"
      ],
      answer: "doubly linked list"
    },
    {
      question: "RLINK is the pointer pointing to the......",
      options: [
        "last node",
        "head node",
        "successor node",
        "predecessor node"
      ],
      answer: "successor node"
    },
    {
      question: "In a linked list, insertion can be done as.........",
      options: [
        "beginning",
        "middle",
        "end",
        "all of the above"
      ],
      answer: "all of the above"
    },
    {
      question: "In a linked list, deletion can be done as.........",
      options: [
        "beginning",
        "middle",
        "end",
        "all of the above"
      ],
      answer: "all of the above"
    },
    {
      question: "The data structure required to check whether an expression contains  balanced parenthesis is",
      options: [
        "Stack",
        "Queue",
        "Tree",
        "Array"
      ],
      answer: "Stack"
    },
    {
      question: "The data structure required to evaluate a postfix expression is",
      options: [
        "queue",
        "stack",
        "linked-list",
        "All of the above"
      ],
      answer: "stack"
    }   ]]
